Diplomatic Documents, 1404-1781 M1814
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Diplomatic documents
1404-1781
M1814
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
0.5 Linear feet 34 manuscript documents
Scope and Contents
Included are 34 diplomatic documents from Italy (predominantly), France, Spain, England, and Czechoslovakia. Of particular note is an 1772 Papal indulgence from Olomouc, in the Czech Republic, and a 1781 letter addressed by Pope Pius VI to Scipione de' Ricci, bishop of Pistoia-Prato, in reply to the bishop's complaint about two nuns of the Monastery of Santa Caterina who are on the road to perdition and whose heresies and misdeeds border on the incredible.
Access to Collection
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2011. Accession 2011-042.
Collection Note
An artificial collection created by the dealer, Bernard M. Rosenthal.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Bernard M. Rosenthal, Inc., Booksellers; Ricci, Scipione de', 1741-1810.; Manuscripts, Italian.; Manuscripts, Latin (Medieval and modern).; Manuscripts, Medieval.; Paleography.; Papacy--History--Sources.; Popes--Correspondence.; Medieval and Renaissance studies--Czech Republic--18th century.; Medieval and Renaissance studies--England16th century.; Medieval and Renaissance studies--France--15th century.; Medieval and Renaissance studies--Italy--15th century.; Medieval and Renaissance studies--Italy--16th century.; Medieval and Renaissance studies--Italy--17th century.; Medieval and Renaissance studies--Italy--18th century.; Medieval and Renaissance studies--Spain16th century.
Collection List
- Treviso, Italy: May 2, 1404 (Half box 1, Folder 1)
- Treviso, Italy: January 9, 1444 (Half box 1, Folder 2)
- Asillo(?), Italy: January, 1448 (Half box 1, Folder 3)
- Asillo, Italy: November 3, 1459 (Half box 1, Folder 4)
- Milan(?), Italy: July 11, 1485 (Half box 1, Folder 5)
- (?): February 6, 1486 (Half box 1, Folder 6)
- France: late 15th century (Half box 1, Folder 7)
  General note
  Calligraphy exercises
- (?): May, 1504 (Half box 1, Folder 8)
- (?): ca. 1509 (Half box 1, Folder 9)
- Salerno (Cava), Italy: June 19, 1518 (Half box 1, Folder 10)
- Venice, Italy: August 18, 1548 (Half box 1, Folder 11)
- Padua(?), Italy: September 5, 1552 (Half box 1, Folder 12)
- Barcelona, Spain: 1565 (Half box 1, Folder 13)
- Burgonvalis: December 14, 1565 (Half box 1, Folder 14)
- Vicenza, Italy: July 28, 1571 (Half box 1, Folder 15)
- Porta Buffoleti: August 10, 1583 (Half box 1, Folder 16)
- Venice, Italy: April 4, 1589 (Half box 1, Folder 17)
  Manumission of a slave
- (?): January 22, 1591 (Half box 1, Folder 18)
- Venice, Italy: April 8, 1591 (Half box 1, Folder 19)
- Venice, Italy: September 20, 1597 (Half box 1, Folder 20)
- Cartina d'Ampezzo, Italy: October 16, 1603 (Half box 1, Folder 21)
- Venice(?), Italy: February(?) 21, 1610 (Half box 1, Folder 22)
- Cortina d'Ampezzo, Italy: October 8, 1619 (Half box 1, Folder 23)
- Bassano, Italy: May 3, 1621 (Half box 1, Folder 24)
- Montebelluna, Italy: April 1, 1626 (Half box 1, Folder 25)
- Bassano, Italy: January 22, 1630 (Half box 1, Folder 26)
- Treviso, Italy: April 16, 1632 (Half box 1, Folder 27)
- Bassano, Italy: 1659 (Half box 1, Folder 28)
- Rome, Italy: September 17, 1678 (Half box 1, Folder 29)
- Rome, Italy: June 1781 (Half box 1, Folder 30)
  Letter addressed by Pope Pius VI to Scipione, Bishop of Prato, in relpy to the bishop's complaint about two nuns of the Monestary of Santa Caterina who are on the road to perdition and whose heresies and misdeeds border on the incredible.
- Rovereto, Italy: March 19, 1485 (Flat-box 2, Folder 1)
- (?): February 3, 1550 (Flat-box 2, Folder 2)
- England: 1598 (Flat-box 2, Folder 3)
- Czech Republic: November 4, 1772 (Flat-box 2, Folder 4)
  Papal Indulgence
- Vellum bookcover, ca. 17th century (Flat-box 2, Folder 5)